<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>You will do foolish things, but do them with enthusiasm on Steve a light on</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/</link><description>Recent content in You will do foolish things, but do them with enthusiasm on Steve a light on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to think and design user interfaces</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/ui-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/ui-design/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working on the design of a website or web page, keep in mind that the beauty of visual style is not the deciding factor for success.
In fact, Vitaly Friedman, co-creator of the smashing magazine, said that &amp;ldquo;usability and the utility, not the visual design, determine the success or failure of a web-site.&amp;rdquo;
Unfortunately, designers tend to conceive trendy looking interfaces, without considering the user&amp;rsquo;s needs. This is a problem, because it leads to a quantity of complex and inappropriate user intefaces.</description></item><item><title>Is UX Design a separate practice from Game Design?</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/is-ux-design-different-from-game-design/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/is-ux-design-different-from-game-design/</guid><description>As video games have been more and more popular, the demand for more user-friendly experiences grew significantly over the years. Thus, UX designers have been the driving force behind the evolution of the video game industry.
Although UX existed since the early days of the Internet (and even before with Taylorism), it&amp;rsquo;s been about 10 years thhe video game industry picked up the practice.
Now, what is exactly UX design ?</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/pages/about/</guid><description>Hi I&amp;rsquo;m Steve Mettraux. I&amp;rsquo;m a media engineer from Switzerland. I studied web development, digital marketing strategy, brand development and UI/UX design at the HEIG-VD, in Yverdon-les-Bains.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a Digital Expert @la Botte Secrète agency, and as a freelance web developer.
My life Everyday, I work on finding inspiration for my project driven life. I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for new challenges and new ways to improve myself. I usually find inspiration while allowing myself to get lost, would it be in the nature or on the web.</description></item></channel></rss>