<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Usability on Steve a light on</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/tags/usability/</link><description>Recent content in Usability on Steve a light on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/tags/usability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Step-up as a programmer</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/step-up-as-a-programmer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/step-up-as-a-programmer/</guid><description>As a newbie programmer, I know I have many flaws and bad practices that I wand to get rid of. And this comes through learning from experienced developpers, reviewing old code and always trying to improve.
Here is a reminder for me, as for everyone else, of the thigs you should try to improve to become a better programmer.
1. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to step out of your confort zone. Development is a vast domain, with tons of languages, framework, tools and so on, so you tend to only use a few of them that you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with.</description></item><item><title>How to think and design user interfaces</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/ui-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/ui-design/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working on the design of a website or web page, keep in mind that the beauty of visual style is not the deciding factor for success.
In fact, Vitaly Friedman, co-creator of the smashing magazine, said that &amp;ldquo;usability and the utility, not the visual design, determine the success or failure of a web-site.&amp;rdquo;
Unfortunately, designers tend to conceive trendy looking interfaces, without considering the user&amp;rsquo;s needs. This is a problem, because it leads to a quantity of complex and inappropriate user intefaces.</description></item></channel></rss>