<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Steve a light on</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Steve a light on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Experimenting Free Frontend</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/experimentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/experimentation/</guid><description>As part of my tech research, I stumbled upon Free Frontend. A curated collection of free hand-picked HTML, CSS and JavaScript (jQuery, React, Vue) code examples, tutorials and articles.
Subject &amp;amp; Objectives I recently developed a small one pager, with a simple HTML5, CSS3 and vanilla JS combination. As I presented it, I was suggested some UI modifications, that I still have to implement at this very moment.
So this is the perfect occasion: try to fit what I find on free frontend on this project.</description></item><item><title>Step-up as a programmer</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/step-up-as-a-programmer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/step-up-as-a-programmer/</guid><description>As a newbie programmer, I know I have many flaws and bad practices that I wand to get rid of. And this comes through learning from experienced developpers, reviewing old code and always trying to improve.
Here is a reminder for me, as for everyone else, of the thigs you should try to improve to become a better programmer.
1. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to step out of your confort zone. Development is a vast domain, with tons of languages, framework, tools and so on, so you tend to only use a few of them that you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with.</description></item><item><title>VSCode extensions I love</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/vscode-extensions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/vscode-extensions/</guid><description>When it comes to technology, there are thousands of tools you could use. How could you know where to start?
For someone who started coding a few years ago, this barrage of information was too vast for me to easily identify.
I am no expert, but I found along the way, by experiencing some tools or reading articles as this one, found some interesting plug-ins that I&amp;rsquo;ll share with you:</description></item><item><title>How to think and design user interfaces</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/ui-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/ui-design/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working on the design of a website or web page, keep in mind that the beauty of visual style is not the deciding factor for success.
In fact, Vitaly Friedman, co-creator of the smashing magazine, said that &amp;ldquo;usability and the utility, not the visual design, determine the success or failure of a web-site.&amp;rdquo;
Unfortunately, designers tend to conceive trendy looking interfaces, without considering the user&amp;rsquo;s needs. This is a problem, because it leads to a quantity of complex and inappropriate user intefaces.</description></item><item><title>Is UX Design a separate practice from Game Design?</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/is-ux-design-different-from-game-design/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/is-ux-design-different-from-game-design/</guid><description>As video games have been more and more popular, the demand for more user-friendly experiences grew significantly over the years. Thus, UX designers have been the driving force behind the evolution of the video game industry.
Although UX existed since the early days of the Internet (and even before with Taylorism), it&amp;rsquo;s been about 10 years thhe video game industry picked up the practice.
Now, what is exactly UX design ?</description></item></channel></rss>