<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development on Steve a light on</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/categories/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development on Steve a light on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Experimenting Free Frontend</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/experimentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/experimentation/</guid><description>As part of my tech research, I stumbled upon Free Frontend. A curated collection of free hand-picked HTML, CSS and JavaScript (jQuery, React, Vue) code examples, tutorials and articles.
Subject &amp;amp; Objectives I recently developed a small one pager, with a simple HTML5, CSS3 and vanilla JS combination. As I presented it, I was suggested some UI modifications, that I still have to implement at this very moment.
So this is the perfect occasion: try to fit what I find on free frontend on this project.</description></item><item><title>Step-up as a programmer</title><link>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/step-up-as-a-programmer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smettraux.github.io/Hugo/posts/step-up-as-a-programmer/</guid><description>As a newbie programmer, I know I have many flaws and bad practices that I wand to get rid of. And this comes through learning from experienced developpers, reviewing old code and always trying to improve.
Here is a reminder for me, as for everyone else, of the thigs you should try to improve to become a better programmer.
1. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to step out of your confort zone. Development is a vast domain, with tons of languages, framework, tools and so on, so you tend to only use a few of them that you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with.</description></item></channel></rss>